<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r4l | Wafa Johal</title>
    <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/tags/r4l/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wafajohal.github.io/tags/r4l/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>r4l</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wafajohal.github.io/img/site-icon.png</url>
      <title>r4l</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/tags/r4l/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>iReCheck</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/irecheck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/irecheck/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 8% of children between 4 and 12 are dysgraphic or encounter serious difficulties in learning handwriting. Dysgraphia, just like dyslexia, can seriously impair the everyday school life of children and have damageable impact on their academic achievements. The detection of such difficulties should be done as soon as possible to minimize its effect on the child’s school performances. And an adaptive remediation should be provided. The CHILI Lab at EPFL showed how a robotic co-learner agent could have positive effects on the child&amp;rsquo;s motivation to practice handwriting. However, motivation is only one aspect that needs to be taken into account in order to provide a long-term adaptive training experience for children learning how to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the iReCHeCk project, we propose a finer characterization of handwriting, as a multimodal activity, taking into account the body posture to capture important features in the handwriting process. We will develop engaging training activities with a robot to monitor the learning status of the child, allowing therapists to evaluate progresses, while adapting the robot&amp;rsquo;s attitude and the training task to the needs of the learner. Our goal being to touch a wide range of handwriting learners, these activities will be tested on two populations: Typically Developed Children that are learning how to write at school; Children with Neuro-Developmental Disorders, presenting handwriting difficulties along with other disorders (i.e. attentional, autistic).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animatas</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/animatas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/animatas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Animatas is a H2020 MCS International Training Network involving 8 insitutions from Europe and several international partners (amoong which UNSW).
The goal of the project is to investigate social learning and embodiement of autonomous agents in learning contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three aspects are investigated at EPFL with some collaborators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modelling Engagement in Collaborative Learning Scenario&lt;/strong&gt; - Jauwairia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can we build a group model of engagement? Can we quantify engagement with regard to learning and find the optimal engagement for the group of learners?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mutual Understanding in Learner-Robot Interaction&lt;/strong&gt; - Utku&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can we build an agent able to detect mis-understanding? to repair them or create them (for the sake of learning)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchestration of Robot Populated Classroom&lt;/strong&gt; - Sina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to enable teachers to manage and monitor their classroom during robotics practical?
What are the advantages and drawbacks of robots in the classroom in terms of teacher&amp;rsquo;s orchestration?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robots for Learning (R4L)</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/robots4learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/project/robots4learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the increasing number of engineering jobs, politics have more recently turned towards introduction of
engineering subjects in early stages of curricula. More and more countries have started to introduce programming
(and even robotics) to young children. However, this constitutes a real challenge for the teaching
professionals, who are not trained for that, and are often skeptical to use new technologies in classrooms.
Hence, the challenge is to introduce robots as tools to be used not only in programming or robotics
based courses, but in the whole curricula in order to make them attractive to teachers as a pedagogical
tool.
”Educational robotics” does not really constitute a research community per say. On one hand, there are scholars
working on ”how to teach robotics” using robotics platforms such as Thymio and Mindstorms. Some scholars
perform research in this domain (for example, measuring which learning activities produce faster learning), but
their numbers are scarce, they typically meet in half-day workshops before ed’tech conferences (CSCL, AI&amp;amp;Ed, ….).
On the other hand, one finds scholars who mainly do research on HRI and consider education as an interesting
place for testing child-robot interactions.
I launched in 2016 a series of workshops to build a Robots for Learning (R4L) research community. The first event
was a workshop, along with the RoMan 2016 conference. The event gathered 30 participants from all around the
world. The second event was a workshop along the HRI 2017 conference in Vienna, Austria, with 60 participants
and 10 presentations. This fall, we hosted the first stand alone event, in Switzerland, for which we invited main
actors of research in HRI for Learning. A new workshop is planned for HRI 2018. These workshops aim to
mix scientists from field of robotics with those from digital education and learning technologies (See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://robot4learning.github.io/&#34;&gt;https://robot4learning.github.io/&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
