<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News | Wafa Johal</title>
    <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wafajohal.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>News</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wafajohal.github.io/img/site-icon.png</url>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>I obtained a DECRA fellowship!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/decra2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/decra2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The SydCHI Local Chapter just got accepted</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/sydchi_accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/sydchi_accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super excited about the new SydCHI local chapter.
Stay tune!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Demo Award at HRI 2020!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/hri2020_demo_award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/hri2020_demo_award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our international team received the best demo award at @HRI2020 @dillenbo @AnaraSandy! #SNSF #CoKaz
&lt;a href=&#34;http://humanrobotinteraction.org/2020/best-paper-awards/&#34;&gt;http://humanrobotinteraction.org/2020/best-paper-awards/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[HRI2020 Paper Accepted!] on Transposing CoWriter to Learning the New Kazakh Alphabet</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/hri2020_accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/hri2020_accepted/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Reviewer Award for ICCE</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/best_reviewer_icce2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/best_reviewer_icce2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am hounoured that the 27th International Conference on Computers in Education awarded me with the Best Reviewer Award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ilt.nutn.edu.tw/icce2019/04_Best%20Reviewer%20Award.html&#34;&gt;http://ilt.nutn.edu.tw/icce2019/04_Best%20Reviewer%20Award.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Full Papers Presented @RoMan 2019, New Delhi!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/roman2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/roman2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was very glad to meet my colleagues and friends at RoMan.
We presented four papers and enjoyed a day off in Jaipur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted! Allohaptic</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/allohaptic2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/allohaptic2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was very glad to meet my colleagues and friends virtually at RoMan2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iReCheck project accepted!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/irechech-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/irechech-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iReCheck project submitted last April will be funded by the French ANR and the Swiss NSF.
The goal of the project is to explore the learning by teaching sceanrio proposed in the cowriter project in with both performance and social adaptation, and with TD learners and learners with NDD.
The project brings educational expertise of the EPFL team with the NDD expertise of the French partners to build a system that can suit all types of learners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging multi-level time scales for HRI analysis</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/framework-hri-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/framework-hri-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You collected Gigabits of multi-modal data from an #HRI experiment? Check out our new paper on THRI proposing an analysis framework based on Newells&amp;rsquo; time scales. w T. Asselborn, K. Sharma &amp;amp;&lt;br&gt;
@dillenbo
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3338809&#34;&gt;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3338809&lt;/a&gt; #HRI2020 #humanrobotinteraction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day at UNSW as Lecturer (Assistant Prof)</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/unsw-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/unsw-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Officially starting at  @UNSWEngineering today. Looking forward to this exciting adventure! Stay tuned, Phd job offers coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex&#39;s Bachelor Design Presentation</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/alex-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/alex-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Super excited about the presentation of my first design intern.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a fruitful experience to work with him this past few months.
Bravo Alex! #epfl #ecal&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London/Brighton UK, One week workshop, Find you Voice project</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/fyv-ukmeeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/fyv-ukmeeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Find your Voice project (seed project, funded by the Jacobs Foundation and the SRCD) aims to investigate the potential use of voice assistant/robot to train children on joke telling to improve their self-confidence and language literacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whole week workshop ehlp us to clearly set objectives for the first part of teh project.
We conducted a small literature review and discussed the mini projects to be conducted by Mai 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop started at UCLIC. Hosted by Prof. Yvonne Rogers, we visited the HCI facilities and the offices of the startup developping the Olly robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After two days in London, we travelled to Brighton, on the sourthen coast of England, were we presented the FyV project to the members of the Chat Lab at Sussex Universty (lead by Prof. Nicola Yulli). The discussions and feedbacks were very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expert for the Focus group on Robots in Education</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_focustaswiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_focustaswiss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The TA Swiss (Swiss Technology Assessment Foundation) invited me to praticipate to a focus group about robotics as an expert in robots for education.
I was glad to present an overview of ther research of robotics in education.
The day ended with a very interesting panl in which many asptects such as ethics, and regulations were discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some pictures of the workshop:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ta-swiss.ch/en/projects/participative-ta/focus-robots/&#34;&gt;https://www.ta-swiss.ch/en/projects/participative-ta/focus-robots/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full report is available here  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ta-swiss.ch/Focus-Robots-Broschuere-fr-web.pdf&#34;&gt;https://www.ta-swiss.ch/Focus-Robots-Broschuere-fr-web.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (in french)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising a Winter School on Developing Technologies in Educational Settings</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/edtech-winterschool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/edtech-winterschool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;22 participants attended the 4 days training event at EPFL on Developing Technologies in Educational Settings.
The winter school recieved the support of the NCCR Robotcs and the Animatas H2020 EU project.
We had invited great speakers and got excellent feedback from the participants.
I specially wanted to thank Florence Colomb, Dr. Jennifer Olsen, Prof. Pierre Dillenourg, Dr. Catharine Oertel, Utku Norman, Jauwairia Nasir and Sina Shahmodari for helping me organising the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official page of the winter school is here:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://chili.epfl.ch/digital_learning_ws/&#34;&gt;https://chili.epfl.ch/digital_learning_ws/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astana! Visiting our partner for the CoWriting Kazakh project</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/visit-cokaz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/visit-cokaz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thibault Assselborn and I travelled to Astana, Kazakhstan to install CoWriter with Anara.
We discussed learning sceanrios to help Kazakh students learn the new Latin Kazakh alphabet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was definitly a fruitful visit, but the weather was not ideal for us to sightsee (-40°C).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk at the HRI 2018 Mini Symposium, Standford CA</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/talk-hris2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/talk-hris2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Teaching children to write using robots with haptic feedback.
I gave a small talk on our IDC paper [?] using the Cellulo robots for a handwriting activity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bold Blog Article on R4L is out</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/writingbold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/writingbold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pierre Dillenbour and I wonder &amp;ldquo;What are robots doing in schools?&amp;rdquo; in a blog post on Bold : &lt;a href=&#34;https://bold.expert/what-are-robots-doing-in-schools/&#34;&gt;https://bold.expert/what-are-robots-doing-in-schools/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demos at NCCR Robotics Industry Days</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/nccr_id2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/nccr_id2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The CHILI Lab presented several demo at the Swiss Converntion Center.
Always a great opportunity to meet with colleagues from the NCCR and robotics actor of the reagion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach activities</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_outreach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This last weekend, we had a booth at the Robotic Showcase of the EPFL Drone Days. In the summer, we received 80 young girls who were doing a coding camp on campus for demos at the CHILI Lab. I also participate to other outreach activities with the NCCR Robotics (Swiss Industry Days) or with the Service for Promoting Sciences – SPS at EPFL by being interviewed by small girls on my job as researcher in robotics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these events we could present some learning activities that we developed for children and explain our research goals. This kind of events are very tiring, people come and go and are often impatient to test. It can occur during the weekend and we can often feel that we could be working on something more valuable for our research instead and it is a waste of time. But I do think that these events help us as researchers. First, it shows the face of scientists to the public, they can talk to us. As a scientist you also hear the concerns that people have with some of your work and it is interesting to try to reassure the public and take into account these ethical concerns. Robotics has had a bad image in the society these past decades, as the 4th industrial revolution announces that many people will loose their jobs. I personally work on assistive robotics and I want to show the public that robots could be beneficial for their life or for society and that we are researching for what applications they can be an added value. You also want to show the limits of AI and Robotics system. We sometimes make our work sound fantastic when writing papers (the limitation section being a small paragraph at the end of the paper), but when running experiments / demo in the wild, you see the limits of autonomous systems and you show the public that you still need a human to be around to interact with the robots. I also helps me to network. I often do user studies and need to find participants for it. I have presented a recruitment sheet during this kind of events and collected contact of people willing to participate to my next experiment. At least once during the showcase, you will meet this guy (more often a guy but could be a woman) that will want to debate with you. This guy is often affiliated to the field, he knows about cs and robotics, he is retired and thinks that we are now going too far. I usually take my time with these people, try to show and explain that we are doing to research and testing new things, that there is a lot of room for improvement, and that I appreciate his feedback. A lot of people think like him and it is interesting as a scientist and developer to build your argumentation for this kind of debate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project CoWriting Kazakh Accepted!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_cokazakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/post_cokazakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We got a new grant for travel mainly that will enable me to collaborate more with Anara Sandygulova from Nazarbayev University. As Kazakhstan is planning to move from Cyrillic to Roman alphabet, we are planning to use the Cowriter setup to motivate children to learn the new alphabet. This work will also continue our work on dysgraphia by collecting handwriting data samples from children in the two alphabet. The goal will be to discover features that are independent of the alphabet to characterize handwriting skills. Excited for my first visit to Kazakhstan. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working on a Computational Thinking application</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/compthining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/compthining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computational Thinking, Kezako? Computational Thinking such a buzz word these days. I got more and more interested by CT when I saw that there was so much debate on its definition and utility to be taught in school. I recently submitted a proposal to get funding for a project dealing with CT but I will not say much more now as it is being reviewed. In July, we received the visit of my good friend Anara from Kazakhstan, who stayed at the lab for a month; just enough to design an experiment and start the development. To get some inspiration we browsed and got some great ideas from the CSunplugged website : &lt;a href=&#34;https://csunplugged.org/en/&#34;&gt;https://csunplugged.org/en/&lt;/a&gt; We chose to work on Sorting Networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an CS engineer you are very familiar with the classical sorting algorithms such as Insertion Sort, Quick Sort and Bubble Sort (Obama’s favorite) but maybe less familiar with the Sorting Networks. Sorting is everywhere and you use sorting machines all the time, each time you do a Google search, as Google is sorting the search results for you to get the most relevant one on the top of the list. This sorting by relevance can be done in multiple ways. Sorting Networks is one of the ways that as the advantage of allowing for parallel processing of the sorting task. In sorting networks, the only operation applied is comparison. Each thread compares elements of the network two by two and tag them as the higher or lower element of the two. Sorting networks can hence be applied to any kind of element as long as they can be compared (numbers, letters, etc). Another advantage of Sorting Networks is that the number of operation (and hence the execution time of the sorting) can be calculated from the just knowing the number of elements to be sorted (the shape of the network is determined at that time also).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honorable Mention Award at IDC2018!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/bpa_idc2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/bpa_idc2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Awarded in #IDC2018 for our study on Deictic Gestures in a Reading Learning by Teaching scenario with a Nao. Checkout the paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3202743&#34;&gt;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3202743&lt;/a&gt; . Bravo
@ElmiraYadollahi
Ana Paiva and
@dillenbo
#CHILI
@nccrrobotics&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New CFP Robots for Inclusive Learning @HRI2018</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/r4lhri2018cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/r4lhri2018cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 4th Workshop on Robots for Learning will focus on Inclusive Learning trying to address how robots&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;could benefit to learners with special needs or disabilities,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve social well-being in learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enhance learners collaborations and creativity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checkout the website for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4l.epfl.ch/HRI2018&#34;&gt;http://r4l.epfl.ch/HRI2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss NCCR Robotics Industry Days</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/nccr_id2017./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/nccr_id2017./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We presented our robotics projects and had some demos for industrial and academics partners.
It is always the best place to network with great actors of robotics in Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zv6nDMQCWCo&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zv6nDMQCWCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERA.Net Plus RUS – Robotics Panelist</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/eraplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/eraplus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a real adventure to travel to Moldavia for this panel meeting for which I was invited, as a HRI specialist, to review russo-european projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Paper Award @HRI2017!</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/bphri2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/bphri2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our paper on the Cellulo project got the Best Paper Award in Vienna at the HRI2017!
We had another study paper and a demo paper at HRI this year with this same project. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing ...</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently or done reveiwing papers  for CHI2017, HRI2017, CSCW2017, IJSORO, Transaction on Learning Technologies and the Journal of Child Computer Interaction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CfP Special Issue in JSORO on Robots for Learning</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/cfpjsoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/cfpjsoro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce that we are launching a special issue on Robots for Learning in the Springer International Journal of Social Robotics.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://r4l.epfl.ch/IJSORO&#34;&gt;http://r4l.epfl.ch/IJSORO&lt;/a&gt;
#R4L #robots4learning&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk @Xerox R&amp;D, Grenoble</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/xerox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/xerox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I gave a seminar at Xerox R&amp;amp;D in a lovely manor near Grenoble.
Glad to see people interested to port their NLP and ML algorithms to robots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviewed by The Long and Short</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/interviewlongshort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/interviewlongshort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interviewed on our Educational Robotics Projects at CHILI/EPFL:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thelongandshort.org/machines/could-robots-teach-our-children&#34;&gt;http://thelongandshort.org/machines/could-robots-teach-our-children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop on Social Robots in Education @NewFriends 2016</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/wsnewfriends2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/wsnewfriends2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am co-organizing a workshop on Social Robots in Education. For more info : &lt;a href=&#34;https://socialrobotsineducation.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;https://socialrobotsineducation.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellulo @ the Robots Zoo, Cambridge Science Festival</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/cellulocsf2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/cellulocsf2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We demonstrated an activity on wind with Cellulo robots at the Cambridge Science Festival.
About 2000 people came to our stand. This demonstration was prepared by all the Cellulo project members. We were kindly invited by Swissnex Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/g_7glQmTIVo&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/g_7glQmTIVo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/s3KAoQNUPZs&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/s3KAoQNUPZs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Translation of Bartneck’s Godspeed Questionnaire</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/frenchgodspeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/frenchgodspeed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently contributed to the translation in French of the godspeed questionnaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This questionnaire aims to measure user’s perception of robots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Touch Grand Challenge @ICMI 2015</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/icmi2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/icmi2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My team and I won the Social Touch Grand Challenge of ICMI 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presented our results at the Grand Challenge session. We had the best scores for recognition of social gestures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit the Personal Robots Group at MIT Media Lab</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/visitmitprg2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/visitmitprg2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk and discussed with some members of the Personal Robots Group. I also got to see Tega, Leonardo and Nexi for real. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no Jibo around yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also took a tour in the MIT Media Lab building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo at Eclipse IOT Day 2014, Grenoble</title>
      <link>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/eclipseiot2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wafajohal.github.io/post/eclipseiot2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Demo using iPOPO, OpenHab via MQTT with Nao as natural remote control of the smart home sensors and actuators. (in collaboration with Shadi Abras, Thomas Calmant and Amr Alyafi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/4vBSJ7csp8g&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/4vBSJ7csp8g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
